In this task, we are given five classes.
Computer, Server, Client, Laptop, and Tablet,
which I've already partially modeled out here.
And for these, we need to figure out a sensible
hierarchy by using suitable generalization groups.
So, looking at these five classes, we need to
first think about which class would make the most
sense being at the top of the hierarchy. That's
going to be Computer because every Client, Server,
Laptop, and Tablet is some kind of Computer. So,
putting the Computer at the top of the hierarchy,
where every other class is going to inherit from
it or indirectly inherit from it in some
way, makes the most sense in this case.
Now looking at the other classes, we have Client
and server, which are pretty distinct use cases
for a Computer. So, we can use that immediately
and just make a generalization group that we call
use cases. And if we get our generalization
arrow from down here and draw an arrow.
You can model it out properly as
well. You can get rid of these labels.
If you want to be very fancy, you can just
spend a lot of time aligning these lines here.
Then you can also make them into sharp
corners if you prefer that. And now,
we have our first generalization group
modeled here. We call it use-cases. So,
we can put a label on it that says use-cases,
making this our use-cases generalization group.
Next up, we have a laptop and tablet remaining.
We need to think about whether they can be part
of this generalization group as well. Well, not
really because Laptop and Tablet aren't use-cases
of a computer. They are kinds of computers.
So, it would make more sense to create a new
generalization group that we call use-cases,
which generalizes from Computer. Alternatively,
at this point, you could also argue that laptops
and tablets specifically are not normally used
as servers but only as clients. So, you could
put them as generalizations of clients. So,
this would be a device-type generalization of the
Client and, in turn, that inherits from Computer
as well. So, Laptop and Tablet are still kinds of
computers, but they are primary kinds of clients.
Of course, you can model them as direct
types of computers because, technically,
Laptop and Tablet could also be servers. So, it
would make sense to have it directly inherit
from Computer and not directly related to
Client and server in any way. If we do that,
we have our second generalization
group. You can get these arrows aligned.
This is not going to be perfect. But it
is what it is. So, this is our second
generalization group. A moment ago, we called it
device-types. So, let's just put that label on it,
device-types. So, this is our
device-types generalization group.
And with that, we have our hierarchy
complete. And now, we need to
determine for every generalization we use.
So, for use-cases and device-types here,
if they are complete or incomplete, and
whether they are disjoint or overlapping.
To determine if a generalization group is
complete, you need to think about if there
are any other possible classes that could
be in the generalization group but that
are not included in the model right now. So, for
use-cases here, for Client and server, normally,
a computer is either a client to something or a
server for something. So, that would make it a
complete generalization group. Now, you could also
argue in this case that you just use your Computer
for gaming, for example. You are not a client for
anything. You are not a server for anything. You
just play offline games, for example. Then your
Computer is neither a client nor a server. So,
this would be an incomplete generalization group.
So, this is where it's important to explain your
choices for each case. We're just going to say,
even if you're playing games, you're still a
client for something. Because how did you get the
game? These days you normally downloaded it.
So, at some point, your Computer was
a client. So, let's say, in this case, this is a
complete generalization group because your Computer
is going to be either a client or a server.
I'm going to leave this incomplete for a moment.
And ask the same question for the device-types
generalization group. In this case, it's pretty
clear that this is going to be an incomplete
generalization group. Because obviously, there are
other devices, other kinds of computers than just
laptops and tablets. There are rack-mounted
computers. There are desktop computers and
Raspberry Pi's, and whatever. Technically your
cell phone is a computer. So, this is definitely
an incomplete generalization group. To note
here, in terms of syntax, you use these curly
braces here to put these labels with complete
or disjoint on them. And now we need to ask
whether they are disjoint or overlapping. To
determine if they are disjoint or overlapping,
we look at the classes currently modeled in the
generalization group. And think if there could
be subclasses of these that inherit from both
of them, for example. So, in the case of device
types, you can have devices like hybrid laptops
or hybrid tablets. Where if you fold them up,
you have a full-size keyboard in them, and it's a
laptop. And if you fold it down, you just have the
screen as a touch screen. And then it's a tablet,
technically. So, this is definitely an overlapping
generalization group. Because you have these sort
of hybrid devices. And for Client and server,
it comes down to how you argue your case
here once again because technically,
your Computer can run a server software and be a
client to something else at the same time, making
your Computer technically both. So, that would
be a case where it's overlapping. Or we could go
with a narrative we've used before. Your computer
is either a server or a client. Therefore,
this would be a disjoint generalization
group. So, let's go with that for the moment.
And say this is a complete generalization group,
and it's disjoint. Because computers can be either
clients or servers. They can never be both. So,
this is both a complete generalization group
and disjoint at the same time. And for our
device-types generalization group, we decided
on incomplete because there are other kinds of
devices. And it's overlapping because it has
these hybrid devices. Now for the second sub-task,
we are supposed to give a possible attribute for
each of three of the classes. So, basically, three
attributes distributed throughout our diagram
here. And they need to capture the property of
the object exactly from that class. That means, if
we think of any attribute, we need to be careful
that the attribute actually belongs only in that class
and in any classes that inherit from that
class. I will give an example. So, for example,
we decide that we want an attribute for the
number of CPU cores. Let's just call it cores.
And we give it a type of Int because you can't
have half a core. It's always whole cores. So,
this attribute here in Laptop doesn't really
make sense. Because your tablet is going to
have some kind of CPU with a number of cores.
Your Computer is going to have a CPU with some
number of cores. Your Client and server as
well. So, just putting this attribute here
in Laptop doesn't really make sense. So, if we
add this to this place over here, that particular
attribute makes the most sense being in Computer
because all the other classes inherit from it. So,
we put in Computer. We have one of
our attributes correctly placed already.
So, this is our number of cores. Clients and
servers will have a CPU of some sort. And they'll
have a number of cores. So, that makes sense to
be in these classes. And it makes sense to be in
these classes, as well, for the same reason. So,
being in the superclass is the right place for it.
Now we need to come up with two more attributes
that we put in any of the other classes.
If we say, for example, laptops have a screen
size, that doesn't really work either. Because
a client will have a screen normally. Server,
not necessarily. But a client will definitely
have a screen most of the time. Tablet will have
a screen. So, putting a screen attribute in Laptop
doesn't really make sense. What else can we put
for a Laptop that wouldn't work for any of these
other ones? For example, you could say the number
of keys on the keyboard. Once again,
you only have whole keys. So, we type it as
Int, an integer as well. And that attribute
only really makes sense in Laptop here because
a tablet doesn't have a keyboard. Technically a
virtual one. But you wouldn't count the
number of keys on a virtual keyboard.
A client doesn't necessarily have a keyboard.
Because it could be a tablet, for example. So,
wouldn't have a keyboard. And a server, most of
the time, has no peripherals at all. So, that
definitely won't have a keyboard, either. So, the
number of keys makes sense being in Laptop here.
For the third attribute, we could come up
with something for a tablet, for example,
and say touchscreen sensitivity. And
that would be a float value. Determining
how accurate your pointer is going to be
or how many degrees is going to be off
from where you actually touch. So, let's say
sensitivity or something or touch sensitivity.
And we put that as a float value because we want
to have that to be really exact. So, this would be
three attributes here: cores in Computer, number
of keys in Laptop, Tablet has touch sensitivity.
And for this one, also going over it for a
moment. The Laptop normally wouldn't have touch
sensitivity. The Computer doesn't necessarily
have touch functionality at all. So, it doesn't
make sense being here. And for the Client, it's
the same case. A client could have a touchscreen,
but it doesn't need to have one. So, doesn't
make sense to have it in here as well.
So, this would definitely be a candidate
for a unique attribute for tablets.
You could also come up with
a couple more here because
you might have come up with something for the
Client. Maybe the IP address, but IP doesn't
really make sense being in Client because every
Computer is going to have an IP address if it's
on a network of some sort. So, maybe a client
could have certain kinds of client software.
Let's put it as a string, as it would be the
name of something. And the server could then
have services that it runs. So, this would also
be a string. And then, we have attributes for
each of our classes. But as it says, you
only need to figure out three of these.